RESUME

Azariah John Samuel

azariahjohnsamuel@gmail.com

Front End Developer

+91-8220077523

Associate - Projects

Cognizant Ltd -Chennai

SUMMARY

Having 4+ years of IT experience, highly passionate web developer and working with multiple well-known global clients, proven record in developing responsive web application. Strong hands-on experience in Front end UI Technologies and developed projects & frameworks in Banking, Insurance and Life science.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Good experience on VUE JS, Angular 7+ and CLI.
- Hands-on experience on Typescript, Nodejs, and Ajax, Jquery,
 JavaScript, JSON.
- Good experience on HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Vuetify,
 Flex Box, Responsive web design
- Awareness about Agile/Scrum
- Agile JIRA Admin and workflows
- o IDE Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Visual studio TFS.
- Operating System Windows 10 / Mac OS
- Cloud -Microsoft Azure Cloud, VMware

EXPERIENCE

DURATION	DESIGNATION	COMPANY	
Oct 2021 - Present	Associate - Projects	Cognizant Ltd, Chennai	
May 2021 - Oct 2021	Technical Operations Associate	Infosys Ltd, Chennai.	
Jan 2020 - May 2021	Senior Executive	Infosys Ltd, Chennai.	
Sep 2018 - Dec 2019	Executive	Infosys Ltd, Chennai.	
June 2018 - Sep 2018	Trainee	Infosys Ltd, Mysore.	

PROJECT SUMMARY

The projects include development, enhancing and supporting new functionalities. Drive to implement the best possible Web-based solutions for clients by understanding their requirements. Helping in building highly dependable solutions and got a chance to work with multiple clients across the globe. Strong hands-on experience in Front end UI Technologies.

PROJECT 1: AbbVie - Sypher

Skills/Platforms used: Vuejs, JavaScript, Chartjs, Vuetify, HTML 5, SCSS, JSON, and Visual studio code.

Brief Description: The Sypher application was used by the client to visualize all the current data about their products and all their metrics and their performance. The application uses Salesforce as its back end and Vue JS as its front end. The front-end consist of multiple reusable components which were developed to get the data from back end and use visualization library like Chartjs to show all the details as per the requirements if the client.

Responsibilities: UI development, involved in agile process, and daily Scrums

to discuss the application development experience to deliver in time.

Developed various components for the frontend using VUE JS.

Team Size: 4 members

Location: Chennai

PROJECT 2: BOSTON PRIVATE BANK US - INVENTORY

Skills/Platforms used: Angular 7, CLI, Typescript, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4,

JSON, JavaScript, and Visual studio code.

Brief Description: In the Inventory application project the requirement of the

client is to integrate all the information of the servers, ESXi host and vCenters

which are on the datacenter and cloud servers which are in the azure cloud in

a single dashboard which is updated 2 time daily. We achieved it by getting the

data of data center devices by using Power-shell, Power cli and a separate set

up to get the data from the Azure cloud and formatted them using power-shell

and stored them as json files in the web server and using angular services we

got the data into the application. Which will have all the information.

Responsibilities: UI development, involved in agile process, and daily Scrums

to discuss the application development experience to deliver in time.

Developed various components for the frontend using Angular 2.

Team Size: 3 members

Location: Chennai

PROJECT 3: INFOSYS LEX- DIAMLER LEARNING CHANNEL

Skills/Platforms used: HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 4 and Visual studio code.

Brief Description: In the Infosys Lex - Daimler Learning Channel project we were building a channel page for a specific client. Infosys Lex is an internal Learning platform. Which contains courses and trainings for the employees. In lex there are different channels of different clients. We built the learning Channel for the Daimler (Mercedes-Benz) using HTML for the structure CSS and Bootstrap for Styling and basic JavaScript for basic functions in the channel.

Responsibilities: UI development, involved in agile process, and daily Scrums to discuss the application development experience to deliver in time.

Developed various components for the frontend using Angular.

Team Size: 2 members

Chennai: Chennai

PROJECT 4: E-KART

Skills/Platforms used: MS IIS, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 4 and Visual studio code.

Brief Description: In the E-Kart application is an E-commerce application. Where the seller can list products to the costumer. The costumer can add the products in the cart and order the products.

Responsibilities: UI development, involved in the team to deploy the application using Microsoft IIS in the test environment.

Team Size: 6 members

Chennai: Chennai

Project 5: Gentle Hands Mahima Charitable Trust

Skills/Platforms used: Angular 8, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 4 and Visual studio code.

Brief Description: The Website for the Charitable trust was Developed as per the client's requirement. It follows the responsive web design.

Responsibilities: This website was designed end to end by me using Angular 8, HTML, CSS and bootstrap. Hosting of the website to the Internet.

Team Size: 1 member

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

COURSE	COLLEGE/UNIVERSITY	PASSING YEAR	PERCENTAGE
MCA	Madras University, Chennai.	2021	Waiting for Result
B.Sc. Mathematics	Madras Christian College, Chennai.	2018	72%
HSC	SSRM School, Salem.	2015	85%
SSLC	SVVM School, Kadayampatti, Salem.	2013	90%

AWARDS & APPRECIATIONS

- Spot Award for Outstanding Performance and valuable Contribution. Infosys Ltd.
- CIS Achievers Award for Best Team. Infosys Ltd.
- Gold Medal for The Best Out Going Student
 Madras Christian College, Tambaram, Chennai.
- First in Department Paper Presentation.
 Madras Christian College, Tambaram, Chennai.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name : Azariah John Samuel

Father's Name : Ebenezer Solomon

Marital Status : Married

Wife Name : Medaline Rachel

D.O.B : 02/08/1997

Passport Detail : \$2951278

Permanent Address : Behind Anjineyer Kovil, Kadayampatti, Salem - 636351

Communication Address : 4/242, Rangarajapuram main road, Santhospuram

(Vijayanagar). Chennai - 600073.